[Music]
for
amen welcome everyone to living Mana
online church I'm excited about today's
message I pray that you are excited as
well and I trust that that is why you
are here uh to hear the word of God so
I'm going to ask that you put a one in
the
chat if you are ready to get into Bible
study today um I'm going to let you know
that today is going to be Bible study
all right we're going to be going going
through the scriptures so I encourage
you to you know get your pen get your
paper whatever you need to do to take
notes of course this is being recorded
so um either way you'll be able to go
back and review this but yall be ready
for some very indepth Bible study I see
all the ones in the chat let's go ahead
and have a word of prayer and we're
going to get right into this let's pray
Heavenly
Father we are coming to you today Lord
ask asking for your divine grace asking
for your
wisdom and Lord we're praying that you
would open the word to
us that we may behold wondrous things
out of
it bless me now Lord as I present the
word may your name be lifted up and
glorified May truth shatter the chains
of error May light shatter the chains of
Darkness
in Jesus name we pray amen amen and so
today's message is entitled who is the
scapegoat who is the scapegoat and the
purpose of this message is actually to
address a series of questions that have
um been uh um that I've gotten some some
notice on social media uh um the
accusation has been made that that
seventh day Adventists uh in particular
are a cult and one of the reasons given
is uh regarding the issue of the
scapegoat who is the scapegoat and what
I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead
and actually play a little clip of a
video that was released by a pastor
asking Adventists a particular question
and this this entire study sermon today
will be dealing with with that question
so let's go ahead and play that clip and
then I'll come back on the other side of
it see shout out to EJ um he talks about
now listen to this Satan is a scapegoat
and ultimate sin Bearer for us so and
they use the Leviticus passage for that
right let's let's read what it says here
Adventist at every level of Advent
adventism uh teach that Satan is the
scapegoat and sin Bearer uh referenced
in Leviticus 16 their official doctrinal
statement of faith seventh day adventage
believes his this is a quote from y'all
a careful examination of Leviticus 16
reveals that a zazil represents Satan
not Christ as some have thought this
Doctrine is closely tied to
investigative judgment and is another
unorthodox and I would say heretical
heretical let me put this on uh sleepy
mode uh real quick let me put this on
sleeping
mode hopefully it's still hopefully oh
it's still recording okay so I'll put it
on sleepy mode because people was
texting me so real quick and so it says
um the doctrine is closely related to
investigative judgment and is another
unorthodox Doctrine held by the SDA
Church Adventists have tortured
scripture listen to make Satan a
scapegoat because Ellen G white look up
Ellen G white the racist woman in the
mid 1800s who is one of the for parents
of the SDA Faith don't don't act like
y'all recanted anything that the LG
white said right uh has it the scape the
scapegoat um typified stat she says and
the author of sin upon whom the sins of
the truly penitent will finally be
placed she repeats Christ will be uh
will place all their sins upon Satan the
originator and instigator of sin the
scapegoat bearing the sins of Israel
went away into a land not inhabited so
Satan bearing guilt of all sins which
has caused God's people to commit will
be the thou will be for Thousand Years
confined on Earth and so you got here
that you all are saying that Satan is
the ultimate sin bear for us this is a
quotation from your Prophet that you all
teach okay so uh this is uh the
gentleman's uh argument that um we are
making Satan our sin
Bearer um because we teach because of
Ellen White that uh the scapegoat
represents Satan when um he and uh
others believe that it is a
representation of Jesus and so he
mentions a book and in the book he's got
a chapter on adventism a chapter that I
have read and I'm going to just uh read
one part of this chapter after speaking
about this investigative judgment and AA
uh the scapegoat it says whereas Satan
is the scapegoat and ultimate sin Bearer
in SDA theology this is not true for
Christians the day of atonement and the
Animals involved are a shadow of Christ
atoning work the goat that died and the
scapegoat in Leviticus 16 represented
one sin offering depicting both the
sacrificial and expiatory aspects of
Jesus's single sacrifice Leviticus 165
Jesus is the one who died for our sins
and also the one who Bears them away he
is the perfect Guiltless one Who Bore
the guilt and sins of others so there
you have it I've just kind of summarized
in a nutshell the argument um and we're
going to get into Leviticus Leviticus
chapter 16 but let me let me clearly
State um what is that what is going on
here what's at stake
here so the
teaching that that uh is being promoted
here is that the scapegoat is
Jesus okay the scapegoat is Jesus put a
one in the chat if you follow that point
so far Point number one they're making
the scape goat is a type of Jesus and if
it's a type of Jesus then that would
mean that the scapegoat is worthy of
worship are y'all with
me now not the actual scapegoat but I
mean the the symbol of the scapegoat so
like we call Jesus the Lamb of God you
know the Lamb of God is worthy of
worship so what they're saying here is
that the not only is the goat which
represented um Christ one goat which
represented Christ worthy of worship but
the scapegoat is also a type of Christ
and thus worthy of worship again I am
not saying that they are saying let's go
worship the scapegoat or any animal I'm
simply saying the type of who the
scapegoat is they say is worthy of
worship so they are also saying that the
scapegoat is our sin Bearer put a two in
the chat if you get that point they are
saying that the scapegoat is our sin
Bearer and they believe the scapegoat is
Jesus so therefore yeah this is our sin
Bearer the
scapegoat uh number three they believe
the scapegoat delivers us from our sins
um and we want to test this we want to
test the idea is the scapegoat
Jesus is the scapegoat the one that
delivers us from our sins is the
scapegoat worthy of our worship because
it's Jesus because it symbolizes Jesus
and and today what I want you to do I
want you to approach this we're in a
courtroom now this is not a sermon we're
in a courtroom and you guys are the
jurry and we're just going to present
evidence we're just going to present
evidence and we're going to look at this
and we're going to comb this thing with
a fine tooth by the way start sharing if
you haven't already shared okay share
with your friends share with your
enemies just hit that share button and
tell them hey the message on who is a
scapegoat is about to start let them
know and and and let let's get as many
people in here as we can okay so let
let's go ahead and begin um Leviticus
chapter
4:20 the Bible says and he shall do with
the bulock as he did with the bulock for
a sin offering so shall he do with this
and the priest shall make an atonement
for them and it shall be forgiven them
now this verse has it this verse is
talking about what the Bible calls the
daily sacrificial
system and what I simply want you to see
here for the moment and by the way guys
what I'm going to ask you to do is
really try to keep the discussion in the
in the in the dialogue box try to keep
that at a minimum and just focus on
what's being said okay I don't want you
guys being diverted I need you to focus
on what's being said okay so uh the text
says that after the sacrifice they would
be forgiven there was nothing else to be
done in these daily Services once the
animal was slain and the blood of
replied the person was forgiven plain
and simple now it was not like this on
the day of atonement so let's go ahead
and go to Leviticus chapter 16 our next
slide in Leviticus chapter 16 this is
the
service um that that was being addressed
in the video um the high priest Aaron
was to take two goats and present them
before the Lord at the door of the
Tabernacle of the
congregation that's Leviticus 16:7 ver8
and Aaron shall cast lots upon the Two
Goats one lot for the Lord and the other
lot for the scapegoat now put a one in
the chat let's just come back let's come
back I'm G take that slide off for a
second we're going to put it back up in
a
moment put a one in the chat if you see
that there are two separate parties here
there is the Lord's goat and then there
is the scape go okay again the argument
is hey these are really the two two of
the same these two symbols represent the
same thing but I just want you to say
follow
along just in a speaking in reality
there are two
distinct entities here there is the
Lord's goat or the goat for the Lord and
then there is the scape goat okay good I
see all the ones let's go ahead and move
to go back to that slide and I want you
to note something here because the the
term for
scapegoat is actually
Azazel and I'm going to read a couple of
different versions here just to let you
see uh Aaron shall cast lots upon the
Two Goats one lot for Jehovah and the
other lot for
Azazel Aaron shall cast lots upon the
Two Goats one lot for Yahweh the other
lot for Azazel then Aaron shall cast
lots for the Two Goats one lot for
Yahweh and one for
Azazel okay so let's come back and here
is my first question for the
jury my first question for the jury is
this do you see here that as Jehovah is
an individual and one goat is for the
individual
Jehovah that this other
goat is for as a
now if Jehovah is an
individual and one go goes to him then
this other goat which goes to Azazel
would make Azazel a what put it in the
chat for me please what would Azazel
be so so we have a comparison here a
goat for this individual and a goat for
what a goat
for this
very good y all this individual so what
I want you to see right off the bat here
is that these goats represent two
individuals two individuals one is
Jehovah the other one then cannot be
Jehovah put a five in the chat if if
that makes sense for you there's 1,443
people 1,43 people watching right now
and it would be nice to see
at43 fives in the chat I know it's not
going to happen but it would be nice do
you see
that one person is
Jehovah and then the other person or
individual cannot be Jehovah otherwise
there would be no need to say that one
of these goats is for Jehovah and the
other is for
Azazel so whoever Azazel is cannot be
Jehovah put a seven in the chat if
you're if you're following so far
whoever Azazel is it cannot be Jehovah
if they were both Jehovah then it would
there would be no need to make a
distinction between them all right so
far so good so far so good so the next
thing we need to address is this why
were lots cast why were lots
cast so this is the only sacrifice in
all of the Bible in which a lot was
required Lots had to be
cast not in any any other sacrifice this
is the one where you had to cast a
lot for these two goats and so naturally
we need to ask ourselves a question well
why why this one and why no other
sacrifice so let's go back to the screen
and the word here for lot the Hebrew
word gor gor uh is from an unused root
meaning to be rough as Stone properly a
pebble that is a lot small stones being
used for that purpose figuratively a
portion or destiny as if determined by
lot okay so let's come
back so as you can see from the
definition itself a lot was used to
determine destiny put a eight in the
chat if you understand what I just said
a lot was used to
determine
destiny therefore we can now begin to
put at least a few things together huh
Two Goats one was for this person
Jehovah and the other is for Azazel this
whoever this person is we now we now
know that if Azazel was Jehovah there
would no there would be no need to make
a distinction
we got two different beings and if the
lots are if the lots are
are okay if the
lot is for a portion or destiny can
y'all hear my mic good I have a red a
little red light on here and it doesn't
mean my mic is dying I'm actually
recording so if y'all can hear me good
then just put a one in the chat very
quickly okay I'm going to keep going
so so then we can see that the purpose
of the Lots was to determine the
destiny of the Lord's goat the the goat
which would represent the Lord and the
destiny of the goat that would represent
a AEL does that make sense we're going
to be doing a lot of numbers so put a
five in the chat if that makes sense the
casting of lots signified that there
were two different
Destinies a
Destiny for the Lord and a Destiny for
Azazel all right come on let's look at a
few
examples uh of why Lots were cast in The
Bible in Joshua chapter 18:6 the Bible
says here uh Joshua 18:6 you shall
therefore describe the land into seven
parts and bring the description hither
to me that I may cast lots for you here
before the Lord Our God you remember
when the children of Israel were getting
ready to get to go into the promised
land they had to cast lots to determine
their inheritance so please keep if
you're taking notes write this down the
casting of lots one of the reasons Lots
were cast was to determine
inheritance what are you going to
inherit what is your future what is your
portion what is your lot how about
another incident of casting lots first
Samuel CH
14 verse 42 and 43 Saul said cast lots
between me and Jonathan my son because
remember in this story Saul tells
everybody don't eat anything Jonathan
actually ends up eating something and
now Saul's trying to find out who is
guilty the Bible says and Saul said cast
lots between me and Jonathan my son and
Jonathan was taken then said to Jonathan
then Saul said to Jonathan tell me what
hast thou done and Jonathan told him and
said I did but taste a little honey with
the end of the rod that was in my hand
and lo I must die all right so put a put
a put a three in the chat I get this
Lots were also used to discover who was
the guilty party put a three in the chat
of y'all are
following Lots were used to determine
who was the guilty party Not only was it
lot you not not was Lot used to
determine this let's go to Jonah 1:7
youall remember the story of Jonah right
and Jonah is on the boat he is running
away from God and then This calamity
comes and notice what they say In Jonah
1:7 then said everyone to his fellow
come let us cast lots that we may know
for whose cause this evil is upon us and
so they cast lots and the lot fell upon
Jonah so we see here that Lots were also
cast to see hey who is the cause of the
evil who is the cause of the evil now
put a fire Emoji in the chat if you feel
that I no longer need to even go any
further with this study I'm going a lot
further but just put a fire fire Emoji
in the chat if you're like Pastor I see
where you're going I'm already ahead of
you okay we're just building this thing
little by little little by little check
this out y'all in Proverbs chapter 16
and verse 33 the Bible says the lot is
cast into the lap but the whole
disposing thereof is the Lord the lot is
disposing thereof is the Lord that word
for disposing is the Hebrew word Mish
poot which means judgment and so one
translation puts it the lot is cast into
the lap but the Judgment thereof is of
the Lord are y'all seeing
this now we can begin to understand that
the casting of lots had to do with
judgment and lo and behold it's quite
interesting that this is the day of
atonement that it's happening on let's
go back to the screen note with me again
the lot causeth contention to cease and
parth between the
mighty whoa so casting of lots causes
contention to cease between two
parties wow so are you telling me Pastor
that you're saying that there is
evidently some kind of contention
between Azazel and Jehovah is that what
you're saying pastor that's what I'm
saying y
that's what the Bible is telling us
there's a
contention there will be different
Destinies for whoever this Azazel is and
the
Lord different Destinies that are that
are represented in these different
ghosts in different goats this casting
of lots has to deal with judgment and lo
and behold isn't it interesting that in
Ezekiel chapter 34:1 17 as for you oh my
flock say the Lord God behold I judge
judge I judge between cattle and cattle
between Rams and the heig gos come on
y'all come on
y'all God judges his C what what God is
telling
us is that he's going to judge his
cattle his flock he's going to judge
between goat and goat and this judgment
causes contention to cease God says okay
here's the GI
here is the innocent so here's what
we've seen so far number one God himself
is judging that's why the casting of the
Lots by the way the reason why the
priest couldn't choose which goat was
which is because to the eye they
look
identical let me not say identical they
were both without blemish if you will
how am I going to determine which goat
belongs to who so no man could choose
that it had to be God's choice and
that's why there was the casting of the
Lots now if it wasn't that important if
it didn't matter if it was the same
individual there'd be no reason to cast
lots because look they're both go
they're both they both got the same
Destiny but that's not the case God says
I myself will choose your eyes will
deceive
you if you try to figure this out on
your own you're going to end up choosing
the wrong goal
100% of the time not 50/50 100% of the
time so here's what we see God himself
is judging the contention is between two
parties it is a deciding of one's future
or portion and there is a determining of
who is responsible for
trouble give me a eight in the chat
y'all if yall following so far put an
eight in the chat if you're following so
far so the Lord's goat is a
representative of Christ the
lord the scapegoat is a representative
of a different
person the other goat cannot also be for
the Lord one goat is for the Lord and if
one goat is for the Lord then the other
goat cannot also be for the Lord
otherwise it would have said both goats
are for the lord and there would be no
distinction now you remember what Jesus
said in Matthew 12:30 Jesus said he that
is not with me he that is not with me is
against me
and he that gathereth not with me
scattereth abroad so let's ask the
question again if if one goat is for the
Lord meaning that he is with me uh
whatever this goat represents it is in
favor of the Lord then this other goat
which was not for the Lord cannot be for
the Lord but against the
Lord he that is not with me is against
me all right so then come on let's
continue to break this all down how are
you jurors doing right now I know we
have some Adventist jurors in here we
have some non-adventist jurors here I
can tell in the chat but listen right
now we're all trying to be responsible
Jers because we have a common enemy
y'all and the common common enemy's name
is Satan it's not y for all the
non-adventist in here right now listen
y'all you are not the enemy and I hope
you would see that of us we are not the
enemy we have a common enemy who is
trying to deceive so either the enemy is
deceiving us or deceiving you or
deceiving us all and and if we love you
and if you love us then yet it's our
responsibility to try to get to the
bottom right to try to figure out how is
the devil trying to make us war with one
another how is the devil trying to do
all this so that's what we're doing
we're in the courtroom and we're we're
we're we're trying to be we're trying to
be fair drawers who are listening to the
evidence and not just throwing stuff out
and be like no I don't believe you
because you're on the opposite side come
on let's go so so what we see here is
that the casting of the Lots represented
a different Destiny for both goats or
the individuals that both goats
represented now here's what's
interesting about that uh uh in Psalm
16:5 the Bible says the Lord is my
portion is the portion of my inheritance
and of my cup thou maintain us my lot
woo the Lord is my portion Lamentations
3:24 save my soul therefore I will hope
with him so let me ask a question how
many of you would definitely like to
have the Lord as your lot if you had to
look at both scapegoats you know for
certain right now that you would like
your lot to be with at least the one
that says this is for the Lord put a two
in the chat if you definitely now I
don't care what side you're on in this
question but every person watching right
now should be putting a two in the chat
that yes I definitely want the lot of
the goat that says that in which the
Bible says was for the Lord because that
goat represents Jesus he is the Lamb of
God he is the sacrifice amen so there is
a portion then for the righteous there
is a lot for the righteous but lo and
behold there is also a lot for the
wicked notice with me Jeremiah 13:4
therefore will I scatter them as the
stubble that passeth away by the wind of
the
Wilderness this is thy lot the portion
of thy measures from me sayeth the Lord
because thou Hast forgotten me and
trusted in
falsehoods
wow the lot there is a lot for the
righteous a
portion and there is a lot for the
wicked and that lot has to
deal with being
stubble and Blown Away by the wind of
the
Wilderness how about Job 2713 this is
the portion of a wicked man with God and
the heritage of op of oppressors which
they shall receive of the almighty there
is a portion for the righteous and
there's a portion of the wicked now the
Bible tells us in Psalms in Proverbs I'm
sorry Proverbs 1 verse 10 the Bible says
my son if Sinners entice thee consent
thou not if they say come with us let us
lay weight for blood let us lurk privil
for the innocent without cause let us
swallow them up alive as the grave and
whole as those that go down into the pit
we shall find a precious we shall find
precious substance we shall fill our
houses with spoil cast in thy lot Among
Us let us all have one purse pause for a
second pause for a
second so from this
idea if we cast our lot with the Lord's
goat the one that says this is for the
Lord then we can know that we have one
lot with
him if we cast our lot with this other
goat for Azazel whoever Azazel is then
we know that we would have a lot with
him and because we know that these lots
are different destinies
we actually have to choose there if if
you're not if there's a lot being cast
you can't choose
both right there's got to you got I
either choose this one or this one
because if you were able to choose both
there would be no reason for a lot being
cast so there are two different
Destinies and whichever goat you cast
your lot with that is who you are stuck
with that's who you
choose so you got two goats two
different Lots two different portions
two different Destinies one of these
goats the scape goat was called the goat
of departure and I find it very
interesting you know when Jesus comes
again check this out y'all know this
look look at the screen with me when the
son of man shall come in his glory and
all the angels with him then shall he
sit upon his throne the Throne of his
glory and before him shall be gathered
all nations and he shall separate them
one from another as a Shepherd
divideth uh
divideth
divideth divideth his sheep from the
goats and he shall set the sheep on his
right hand but the goats on the left
then shall he say unto them on the left
hand depart from me
remember the scapegoat is also called
the goat of
departure depart from me you cursed into
Everlasting fire prepared for the devil
and his angels so the point that I want
to make here we still don't know who
this who this go is we haven't presented
that case yet we just know that there
are God when Jesus comes again he's
going to do a casting of lots of
sorts hey all that were for me enter
into my kingdom all that were against me
me will not enter into my kingdom but
you will depart depart from me you
workers of that's what the text depart
from me you workers of iniquity depart
Go away You're going to be sent away
you're going to be Cast Away so let
let's go into a little bit more detail
and by the way put a seven in the chat
if y'all are following me so far because
I just want to make sure that I'm not
losing anybody right I want I don't want
to lose friend or fo as we go through
this study so just put a seven in the
chat if you're like Pastor we're
following I may not agree with you but
I'm following what you're saying right
now okay good good good so let's check
out this idea of this goat and what else
do goats represent in the Bible let's go
back to the Bible and in Leviticus 17:7
the Bible says and they shall no more
offer their sacrifices unto Devils after
whom they have gone a whoring this shall
be a statute forever for them throughout
their Generations now here's what's
interesting I'm going to read this same
verse in several different translations
and you might be fled about this they
are no longer the isv they are no longer
to slaughter their sacrifices to the
goat
demons with whom they have committed
prostitution the same word used for
Devils is translated in other Bibles as
goat
demons the cev don't ever turn from me
again and offer sacrifices to goat
demons the Erv in this way you will stop
being unfaithful to me by offering
sacrifices to your goat Gods the
ESV so shall they no more sacrifice
their sacrifices to Goat demons after
whom they so the Bible talks about
this this entity called the goat
demons goat demons did y'all know
that did y'all look up the uh
now I'm not saying that these what's
happened in Leviticus 16 at least not
yet but I'm just letting you know that
there is the application of goats in
certain cases to
Demons why is this important to
understand if we go back to Leviticus
chapter 16:5 the Bible says he that is
the high priest shall take of the
congregation of the children of Israel
two kids of the goats for a sin offering
and one RAM for a burnt offering so what
I want you to realize here is this and I
need you all to listen very closely
listen very
closely the text actually says and he
shall take of the congregation of the
children of Israel two kids of the goats
for
sin for sin the word offering is not in
the
text so if you were to look up the he
the Hebrew of this word here it is chat
here's what it says an offense sometimes
habitual sinfulness and its penalty
occasions sacrifice or experation also
concretely an offender punishment of
sin so in other words these two goats
are being offering offered because of
sin put a five in the chat if you
understand what I'm saying here these
two goats were being offered because of
sin almost as a punishment for
sin this same word sin is used 29 4
times in the Bible 214 times it's simply
translated as Sin 72 times it's
translated as sins plural and three
times is translated as punishment so for
example in Genesis 18:20 we read and the
Lord said because the Cry of Sodom and
Gomorrah is very great uh and because
their sin is very Grievous that's the
word sin that is the same word sin that
is used as Sin offering in Leviticus 165
why because the wages of sin is what
is death but the gift of God is eternal
life so both of these Lambs are be both
of these These heot are going to be
punished for
sin and here's a word punishment in in
Lamentations 4:6 for the punishment of
the iniquity of the daughters of my
people is greater than the punishment of
the sin of Sodom same word that's used
there translated as punishment this
shall be the punishment of Egypt and the
punishment of all Nations that come not
up to keep the Feast of Tabernacles
Zechariah 14:19 so then what we see is
that both L both goats were to be
punished now let me ask you a
question is was Jesus punished for sin
yes or no put it in the chat for me was
Jesus punished for sin yes or
no all right the yes the yeses are
coming in absolutely this is common
Christianity y' Jesus was punished he
was he suffered on our behalf not
because of his own sins because he
didn't have any but because of our sins
we don't need to go through the Bible to
demonstrate that now was this Justice or
Mercy which would you say Jesus dying
for our sins was was that Justice or
Mercy how many of you would say yes it
is just that Jesus died for our sins
no no no y'all this is pure
Mercy 100% Mercy now here's my next
question will Satan be punished for sin
put it in the chat for me please yes or
no will Satan be will Satan also be
punished for
sin yes or
no yes and what is that is that Mercy or
Justice
which is it Mercy or
Justice is it Mercy that Satan's going
to be punished for sin no it is Justice
if Satan does not suffer for sin yet we
suffer for sin I say hey I reject Christ
am I going to suffer for my own sins
absolutely any man that says I I reject
Christ I reject I don't want anything do
with God guess what you are going to
suffer for your sins why because the
wages of sin is death so if Satan does
not suffer for sins and the sins that he
has caused where is
justice where is the God of
Justice so come on let let's let's
begin let's begin to break this down
y'all check this out come with me to
Ezekiel CH
28:14 because now we're about to find
out who Azazel is Ezekiel 28:14 the
Bible says speaking of Lucifer speaking
of Satan the Bible says Thou Art the
anointed cherub that coverthe so so an
anointed cherub for those of you that
that don't know was it was the highest
angel or the the angel that stood
closest to the presence of God that
angel in the sanctuary on Earth was the
angel that was carved out and covering
The Mercy Seat was in the presence of
God was in the sanctuary so we already
are beginning to see Sanctuary language
here here is an
angel that dwell in the midst of the
Throne of God the house of
God I have set thee so thou was upon the
holy mountain of God thou walked up and
down in the midst of the stones of fire
thou was perfect in thy ways from the
day that thou was created now I need
y'all to see what the word perfect means
here so here is the word perfect it
means
entire Integrity truth without blemish
without blemish without
blemish without
blemish full perfect sincerely sound
without spot without
spot without spot come on
y'all without
spot in Leviticus 16 you have two goats
that appear blameless that appear
spotless interesting
one is for the Lord and the other
represents this other character whose
name is
Azazel the text goes on in Ezekiel 28:16
to say by the multitude of thy
merchandise they have filled the midst
of thee with violence and thou has sin
so this Angel Lucifer was filled with
violence was filled with iniquity a
whole bunch of iniquity was on him and
as a result watch this therefore I will
cast thee
out as profane out of the Mountain of
God and I will destroy thee Oh covering
cherub from the midst of the stones of
fire Verse 18 thou Hast defiled thy
sanctuaries wait a minute
what what do you mean thou Hast defiled
this is sanctuary language here here is
this heavenly being who's in some kind
of sanctuary who has defiled the
sanctuary and as a result of all the sin
that is upon him he is cast out of the
sanctuary he is cast out he is sent
forth because of the iniquity of thy
traffic therefore will I bring forth a
fire in the midst of thee it shall
devour thee and I will bring thee to
ashes upon the Earth in the sight of all
them that be holy now why is this so
interesting y'all here's why this is
interesting because in Leviticus 16: 211
the Bible says and Aaron shall lay both
his hands hands upon the head of the
live goat this is the goat that was for
a AEL and confess over him all the
iniquities of the children of Israel
every sin is now about to be put on him
and all their transgressions and all
their sins putting them on the head of
the scapegoat and sending him away
sending him away let's look up the word
for sending away and here is the word it
is the word shalak meaning to send away
for or out to cast
away to Cast
Away to push away to put away so this
goat was cast out was was cast away from
the
sanctuary how
significant who could this goat
be this goat of
departure this goat who is not for the
Lord but something
else interesting that in Isaiah 14:12
the Bible says how art thou Fallen oh
Lucifer from heaven son of the morning
how art thou cut down to the ground
which did weaken the Nations for thou H
has said in thine heart I will Ascend
into heaven I will exalt my throne above
the stars of God I will sit also upon
the Mount of the congregation in the
sides of the north I will Ascend above
the highest of the CL I will be
spotless I will be perfect I will be
like the most
high yeah yet Thou shalt be brought down
to Hell to the sides of the pit they
that see thee shall narrowly look upon
thee and consider thee saying is this
the man that made the Earth to tremble
that did Shake kingdoms that made the
world as a Wilderness whoa whoa whoa
whoa that made the world as a Wilderness
and then it goes on to say but Thou Art
cast out of thy grave like an abominable
Branch how interesting all right how are
we doing so far how are y'all doing so
far put a five in the chat if you're
following so far because now now we're
about
to
begin cuz that was just setting the
foundation y'all and yeah I know listen
listen when when when someone says hey
this is a cultic belief this is you guys
are cult like you can't just answer with
a you know two-minute response da this
is what so we're going in depth with
this are y'all ready I hope you're
sitting
down so how many of you have uh you know
what AI is AI I want you to check this
out y'all so I jumped on to to to Ai and
I asked this question um who is Azazel
let's go to the screen who is Azazel and
we're going to jump through this let me
tell you this these slides guys there's
a there will be a QR code at the bottom
of the screen you can get access to
these slides to scan that QR code if
you're on your phone you can just click
the link if you're watching on the TV
take use your phone take a picture of
the QR code you will see it I think it's
going to be at the end of the slides you
get all my slides all of them all right
check this out y'all AI according to AI
I asked a question who is Azazel here's
a response Azazel is a fallen angel in
Jewish and Christian Traditions who is
often associated with demonic forces in
some interpretations he is understood as
a leader of the Fallen Angels who
rebelled against God and was cast out of
the out of heaven in The Book of Enoch
Azazel is described as one of the
chief one of the chief gregori a group
of Fallen Angels who made it with human
women resulting in the birth of Nephilim
now here's what I'm going ask yall
y if someone who is teaching
you that Azazel is
Jesus oh oh
man oh man oh man oh man if you are
wrong on this what else what a and this
is pretty big you're telling me hold on
hold on hold on hold on so I went back
to AI chat and I said okay is Azazel
Jesus here's what AI chat said Azazel is
not Jesus Azazel is often portrayed as a
fallen angel in various religious texts
not just the Bible in various religious
texts particularly in Jewish and
Christian itions in some interpretations
Azazel is associated with rebellion and
sin and is sometimes depicted as a demon
or tempter who leads people astray come
on y'all let's let's keep going let's
keep going Jesus on the other hand is a
central figure in Christianity Jesus on
the other hand on the other hand is a
central figure this hey AI chat is not
Adventist y'all it's it's SDA not a not
AI it's not s d AI
AI chat is not
Adventist Jesus on the other hand is a
central figure in Christianity and is
believed to by Christians to be the Son
of God and the savior of humanity oh man
y'all see this come on come on let's
keep going so I said hey is AEL a type
of Jesus no Azazel is not a type of
Jesus Azazel is commonly considered a
fallen angel in Jewish and Christian
mythology mythology often associated
with rebellion and sin you guys I need
y'all to see this when people throw out
stuff like oh they're a cult because
they believe this or that like don't
just fall for it don't just don't just
like oh they're a cult okay I get you I
agree don't like really look into what
they're saying right come on we're not
done we are just
beginning so so you can even buy your
Azazel sigle sigle of Azazel Satan seal
demon symbol t-shirt sweater actually
you can buy your as AEL demon sweater on
Amazon y'all on
Amazon let's keep going so you go to
Google and you just type in Azazel
here's what you'll see Azazel is a demon
or evil spirit in Jewish Legends in
Christian demonology Azazel as a fallen
angel counted among Satan's hosts he's
described as a Shaggy and terrible
monster and symbolizes chaos destruction
and Corruption Azazel is also known as
The Arc demon or Grand Duke who commands
Legions of demons listen to yall if
someone is telling you that Azazel is
Jesus Azazel should be worshiped I need
y'all to understand that that person may
not understand what they're saying and I
doubt because if they knew what they
were saying they wouldn't be saying it
but I need you to understand that Satan
is behind
that I need y'all to understand this I'm
not making this stuff up let's go back
to the screen let's go back to the
screen okay so so here is uh um here is
uh as El and the practice of magic an
article by Michael Ford on February 25th
Azazel to luciferians is not only a name
of strength power and wisdom yet also an
ancient demonic God and spirit of deific
power Azazel is the bearer of the black
Flame the Divine consciousness of
humanity Azazel originally developed in
Hebrew text as a fallen angel demon
which goats were offered to as part of
their religion oh man let I there are so
many of these I'm just going to kind of
here's the torah.com th torah.com Azazel
plays the role of a deity in the
biblical ritual of yan kapor and in
early to interpretation he played a
central role as the instigator of sin
and even the devil or alternatively as a
protective figure later Traditions
obscured his identity presenting Azazel
as the name of a demon as a scapegoat
itself or even the place name listen
y'all come on come on here's your here's
a picture that people have of people
make of Azazel a goat head Azazel y'all
the one that people are telling you you
should worship the one that Christians
who are telling you Adventists are a
cult are telling you you guys should
worship
Azazel you can buy your demon alter
cloth your Azazel goat demon alter cloth
um I'm not selling stuff I'm just
telling you luciferian apocrypha
branica here's encyclopedia britanica
Azazel in Jewish Legends a demon or evil
spirit to whom in the ancient right of
Yong Kor a scapegoat was sent bearing
the sins of the Jewish people two male
goats were chosen for the ritual one
designated by lots for the Lord the
other for Azazel I'm not going to read
all these because it's too many here's
the Jewish virtual library the Jewish
virtual library this uh uh just as the
first goat is set aside for the Lord so
the second is set aside for Azazel
Azazel being a parallel to the Lord this
view is reinforced by the widespread
belief that the Wilderness was the
habitat of demons the Demonic
identification would indicate that the
original purpose of the ritual was to
get rid of the evil by banishing it to
its original Source wow the Jewish
virtual library beloved are not
Adventists in comic Marvel books there
is a figure named Azazel
his Alias is Satan beel
above come on come on come on
y'all irus the church father irus who
many Christians love to quote Church
fathers which Satan thy true father
enables thee to still accomplish by
means of Azazel that fallen and mighty
Angel there's arenus how about origin
origin I'm G just read this last part
speaking of Azazel was none other than
this and it was necessary that it be
that to send it away to the desert and
to treat it as an expiatory sacrifice
because on it the lot fell for all who
belong to the worst part speaking about
Azazel on account of their wickedness
being opposed to those who are God's
Heritage are deserted by God origin is
saying the goat is sent out into the
Wilderness to represent it being
deserted by God which will be the faith
of the wicked same origin says this the
day of atonement remains for us until
the sun sets listen to this y'all origin
is saying that until Jesus returns the
judgment will be going on the day of
atonement remains for us until the sun
sets that is until the world comes to an
end
whoa for let us stand before the gates
waiting for our high priest who remains
within the holy of holies that is before
the father and intercedes not for the
sins of everyone but for the sins of
those who wait for him for he does not
intercede for those who come into the
lot of the heot which is sent into the
Wilderness he intercedes only for those
who are of the lot of the Lord wow it
hey is origin a Seventh Day Adventist
cuz it sure sounds like it right about
now this is not an Adventist teaching
y'all this is not or Ellen White said
that Satan represent the when people say
that they ex they are playing on your
ignorance and you just think oh yeah
Ellen White said it and therefore she
made it up and those Adventists all they
do is follow what Ellen White says come
on let's keep moving let's keep moving
let's keep going Jewish encyclopedia
Azazel the name of a supernatural being
mentioned in connection with the ritual
of the day of atonement after Satan for
whom he was in some degree a preparation
Azazel enjoys the distinction of being
the most m mysterious extrahuman
character in sacred literature how about
this one new and World New World
Encyclopedia Azazel was a mysterious
desert demon to whom the ancient
Israelites sacrificed a scapegoat on the
day of yam kipor or else a rugged Cliff
upon which the scap was scapegoat was
cast down to atone for Israel's sins the
only mention of Azazel in the Torah is
found in the Book of Leviticus which God
which describes God ordering the high
priest Aaron to place the Lots upon the
Two Goats one marked for the Lord and
the other marked for Azazel New World
Encyclopedia goes on to say that Azazel
was even considered by people like
noades who was a Hebrew uh
commentator that this is a goat likee
demon haunting the desert new world and
cyclopedia same thing H uh The Book of
Enoch the whole earth has been corrupted
through the works that were taught by
Azazel to
ascribe to him ascribe all
sin wow
now we don't teach you know that the
Apocrypha is is is authoritative but I'm
just saying there it is in the Book of
Enoch there it is in the Book of Enoch
okay come on let's keep moving in his
commentary on Leviticus I'm not even
going to read that y'all will get my
slides I'm going to skip this who is
Azazel mythology. net who is Azazel a
fallen angel whose evil influence led to
the corruption of humanity how about
this uh uh dictionary.com Azazel the
demon or place in the wilderness to
which a sacrificial goat is released in
an atonement ritual uh H H um uh where
is this from Azazel is a fallen angel
associated with the forbidden knowledge
of the right of the scapegoat in
traditional Jewish rituals according to
the expositors Bible commentary Azazel
is the Hebrew word scapegoat and it goes
on and beloved listen it goes on and on
Webster Miriam Webster's
Dictionary this the English scapegoat is
a compound of the archaic verb Escape
which means Escape or Escape which means
escape and goat and is modeled on a
misreading of the Hebrew Azazel which is
probably the name of a demon okay y'all
Leviticus 168 we're coming back to the
Bible how are y'all doing so far let
let's come back for a moment how are
y'all doing so far are we
okay do you see put a five the chat if
you now realize that Adventists did not
come up with the teaching that Azazel is
Satan put a five in the chat if you see
that no this is not some off in the
corner teaching even Marvel comic books
The Witches the demons the the
Witchcraft people all say yeah that's
Satan they don't say Jesus is Satan they
know who Jesus is but they say yeah this
is Satan now beloved if if you are so
off in your interpretation of the Bible
to come to the conclusion that someone
who is pointed to as Satan you're saying
that's Jesus and if you don't believe
that's Jesus you're in a cult beloved I
I would be very wary of whatever else I
in fact the next Church you go to just
ask him hey who is Azazel and if they
say AEL is Jesus you need to be like
you're not studying your Bible why would
I want to be in a place that is not
studying their Bible what else you going
to tell
me what else you going to tell
me you are making Satan your sin
Bearer we're not making Satan our sin
Bearer we're not teaching
that Satan died for us we're not
teaching that Satan no no no no no no no
when you say yes as aelle is the sin
Bearer Azazel is who we should worship
beloved listen to me open your
eyes just because something is not in
the mainstream doesn't make it not true
otherwise we should have never followed
Jesus
come back with me to the screen let's
how how y'all doing we're almost there
guys we we are halfway there yeah yeah
yeah I told you today was going to be a
study we're halfway there check this out
ready go let's go to the screen
Leviticus
168 different translation where I will
show you which goat will be sacrificed
to me and which will be sent into the
desert to the demon Azazel yo the
Contemporary English version of the
Bible literally puts the word demon
Azel now beloved let me tell you
something y'all non-adventist watching
right now let me tell you
something do not be
lazy many people are going to be lost
because of laziness oh well I heard on
huh that they uh and so yeah it's
true
yeah don't be lazy
y'all do not be
lazy the devil is after as many Souls as
he can
deceive and don't be thrown off by oh
they're a cult don't be thrown off by oh
they follow this don't you know for
yourself let's go to the screen
Leviticus 16:28 26 the one who led the
goat into the desert and sent it off to
the demon Azazel must take a bath and
wash his clothes before coming back back
into the camp that's a different
translation here's another translation
and Aaron shall offer his bullet oh no
no no we're going to stop right there so
how yall doing so far let's come back
let's come back we're about to move into
another stage of of of our courtroom
session how y'all doing so far how's the
evidence coming along how's the evidence
coming
along are y'all
good are y'all good okay now now we're
about to actually get into what happened
on the day of atonement and y'all need
to see something absolutely crucial here
so let's go back to the screen and we're
going to run through this several verses
but I want you to notice something here
Aaron shall offer his bulock for the sin
offering in fact let me see something
let me see something okay so here we go
on the day of atonement there were four
animals that were used there was the
bulock the RAM and then two heot please
follow this carefully y'all Aaron shall
offer his bulock of the sin offering
which is for himself and make an
atonement for himself and for his house
so here's what I want you to see here's
what I want you to see the bulock it
we're told what the Bullock would make
an atonement
for so the bulock was to make an
atonement for the high priest and his
household are y'all with me so
far okay very good uh um and Aaron shall
bring the bulock of the sin offering
which is for himself so I want you to
know that every time an and a sacrifice
is mentioned it'll tell you who the
atonement was for or what it was for so
Aaron shall bring the bullet of the sin
offering which is for himself and shall
make an atonement for himself and for
his house and he shall kill the bulock
of the sin offering which is for himself
verse 15 then he shall kill the goat of
the sin offering that is for the
people and bring his blood within the
veil and do with that blood as he did
with the blood of the bulock and
sprinkle it upon the mercy seat and
before the mercy seat and he shall make
an atonement for the holy place place
because of the uncleanness of the
children of Israel and because of their
transgressions and all their sins so
shall he do for the Tabernacle of the
congregation that remaineth among them
in the midst of their uncleanness so
what I want you to see here beloved is
that both the bulock and the ram is
included in the bulock sacrifice so the
bulock the RAM and the Goat that was for
the Lord every time they are mentioned
it says atonement for the people for the
house for the sanctuary for the temple
are y'all with me so far
verse 17 and there shall no man there
shall be no man in the Tabernacle of the
congregation when he goeth in to make an
atonement for in the Holy place until he
come out and when he has made an and
when he and let me start it start that
again and have made an atonement for
himself and for his household and for
all the congregation of Israel so now I
want you to know between the bulock the
RAM and the Goat that was for the Lord
atonement was made for everything the
people the holy place the altars Etc now
now watch
this and when he has made an end of
reconciling the holy place and the
Tabernacle of the congregation and the
altar he shall bring the live goat so
pause for a second y'all pause for a
second and here's my question to you
when the live goat is finally brought
into the picture is all the atonement
for the people the temple the priest is
all that done yes or
no put it in the chat for me please is
all that done is everything that needed
to be done to make atonement for the
people the heo that was for the Lord the
priest the bulock and the ram the temple
the heot and the bulock and the Rams
blood was all of that cleanse was all of
that was atonement made for all of that
very good very so whatever atonement
this live goat is going to make has
nothing to
do did y'all catch
that this atonement is something
different it's not the same kind of
atonement that the heo that the that the
goat for the Lord is making this is
something different
yes yes yes yes yes come back with me to
Leviticus 16 verse 21 Leviticus 16: 211
and Aaron shall lay both his hands upon
the head of the live goat and confess
over him all the iniquities of the
children of Israel and all their
transgressions and all their sins
putting them upon the head of the goat
and shall send him away by the hand of a
fit man Into the
Wilderness why let me go back here
why are they put on the head of this
goat may I suggest to
you look at Leviticus 16:22 and the Goat
shall
bear upon him all the iniquities unto a
land not inhabited and he shall let the
goat go into the Wilderness why is the
goat bearing sins is it for the
people check this out
then thou will when thou then hear thou
from heaven and do and judge thy
servants by requiting the wicked by
recompensing his way upon his own head
and by justifying the righteous by
giving him according to his
righteousness so according to 2
Chronicles chapter 6 verse 23 when God
justifies the wicked what does he also
do when he justifies the Wicked on one
hand he also does
what
recompenses or puts the wickedness of
the wicked upon his own head put a one
in the chat if you see
that when God judges or or or verifies
or makes right justifies the righteous
he also REITs the wicked by recompensing
his way on his own
head that's
Justice notice with me Psalm 7:16 his
misch Mischief shall return
upon his own head and his violent
dealings shall come down upon his own
Pate yes yes yes the scapegoat beloved
does not make atonement for the priest
does not make atonement for the people
does not make atonement for the
sanctuary that listen to me Satan must
make atonement for himself in other
words he must bear the punishment of his
own iniquity and what is the atonement
very simple the wages of sin is death
and whereas Jesus could take those wages
and pay it and have enough in him to
bring himself back to
life Satan doesn't have that much money
Satan doesn't have that much Satan
cannot lay his life down and pay a
penalty and pick it up
again Satan will bear the sins of all
that he has done which includes leading
other people to
sin Jesus has enough in himself to pay
the wages of sin die and come back to
life Satan doesn't have
that listen this is check this out y'all
Ezekiel 40:4 we're almost there and the
Levites that are gone away far from me
when Israel went went astray which went
astray away from me after their Idols
they shall even bear their iniquity
verse 12 because they ministered unto
them before their idols and caused the
house of Israel to fall into iniquity
therefore have I lifted up my hand
against them say the Lord God and they
shall say with me everyone bear their
iniquity Leviticus 24:15 and thou
shallal speak unto the children of
Israel saying whosoever curseth God
shall bear his sin beloved when Jesus
bore our sins it was an act of Mercy he
died that we might live when Satan has
all the sins placed on him it is an act
of Justice he will
die he will die for all that he has done
and anything less than that beloved is
not
Justice Leviticus 16:10 it says but the
goat on which the lot fell to be the
scapegoat shall be presented alive
before the Lord to make an atonement not
for but with
him and let him go as a scapegoat Into
the Wilderness please note that in every
case the bulock the ram the he goat it
was all oh this is an atonement for the
people for the temple for the sanctuary
for this for that when it comes to the
scapegoat Azazel you're going to make an
atonement with
him it's not for the people it's with
him
you see beloved Christ died for
us Satan will die but he doesn't die for
us God commanded his love toward us in
that while we were yet sinners Christ
died for us so Christ in Hebrews 9:28 so
Christ was once offered to Bear the sins
of many beloved what it means that when
he saying he was offered it means he
died the scapegoat does not it it is not
sacrificed there is no
blood check this out y'all the atonement
all right all right we are all listen
y'all give me y'all give me just a
little bit more time all right we're
almost done we're almost done I got a
few more absolutely important points to
to nail this thing in the coffin but I
need y'all to follow along so that word
for atonement here is a word on the
screen
the word atonement means to cover or
appease make atonement cleanse disal
forgive be merciful pacify pardon to
pitch to purge away to purge away so
part of the purpose of an atonement was
to purge or put off or send away or
separate Sin from
something for example in Ezekiel 20:38
the Bible says and I will Purge out from
among you the rebels and them that
transgress against me I will bring them
forth out of the country where they
sourn and they shall not enter into the
land of Israel an atonement beloved is
happening here in that those who were
Wicked were being purged out or
away from God's people it was an
atonement but not with blood I'll give
you another example here's the story of
Phineas y'all remember Phineas the
priest that went in and killed the man
and the woman with the javelin the Bible
says in numbers 25:7 and when Phineas
the son of Eleazar the son of Aaron the
priest saw it he rose up from among the
congregation and took a javelin in his
hand and went after the man of Israel
into the tent and thrust both of them
through the man of Israel and the woman
through her belly so the plague was
stayed from the children of Israel and
it goes on to say and he speaking of him
getting the priesthood he shall have it
and his seed after him even the Covenant
of anever lasting priesthood because he
was zealous for the for his God and made
an atonement for the children of Israel
what was the
atonement that Phineas made it was in
removing a wicked doer from the presence
of the
people now we're not going to say that
this man that died was a type of Jesus
no this is a wicked
man this is a wicked man and yet
atonement was
made through the the death of the
wicked oh come on y'all come on you see
listen the one those who take the lot of
Jesus like the the Lord's goat died the
the the scapegoat lived you know the
Bible says he that loses his life for my
sake shall find it but he that seeks to
save his life will lose it beloved
that's the two Destinies of these two
goats
that's the two Destiny of these two
goats Jesus died but he will live
forever
Satan he will face Eternal
death come on come on want y'all to see
this we are almost there y'all we are
almost there Leviticus 16 Leviticus 16
verse 7 verse 17 and there shall no man
be in the Tabernacle of the congregation
when he goeth in to make an atonement in
the Holy place until he come out and
have made an atonement for himself and
for his household and for all the
congregation I need y'all to understand
that that that when the high priest went
into the
temple it was not until he had finished
the work of atonement that the scapegoat
then received his
Destiny do y'all see this it is not
until Jesus leaves Heaven that the
scapegoat will receive his
Destiny but there is a type that we can
look at that kind of gives us an
indication do y'all
remember did Jesus ever have lots cast
over
him yeah he did didn't he when he was at
the
cross and do you remember
that that that experience where Jesus is
about to be crucified the Bible says in
Mark 15:7 there was one named Barabas
which lay bound with them that had made
Insurrection with him who had committed
murder in the
Insurrection
barabus Barabas literally means son bar
Abba son of the
father some translations read it like
this at the time a well-known terrorist
named Jesus barabus Jesus Son of the
father was in jail The Good News Bible
at that time there was a well-known
prisoner named Jesus Son of son of the
father Barabas the Leb version and at
the time they had a notable prisoner
named Jesus Son of barabus beloved
listen to me barabus was a murderer and
a liar and a
thief but the people because they lacked
discernment chose a murderer and a liar
and a thief chose the wrong son of the
Father and Jesus is telling us at the
end of time he says this listen to me
then then watch the screen y'all then If
any man shall say unto you Lo here is
Christ or there believe it not for there
shall arise false Christ and false
prophets and shall show great signs and
wonders in so much as if it were
possible they shall deceive the very
elect behold I have told you wherefore
if they shall say unto you behold he is
in the desert he is in the wilderness
that's him in the wilderness Azazel yes
that's him y'all come on let's worship
him that's him go not forth don't
follow beloved Jesus is the goat he is
the greatest of all times he is the
greatest of all he is the goat but Satan
is also the goat he is the greatest
sinner of all times he is the greatest
deceiver of all times I need y'all to
understand that beloved which goat are
you going to follow Azazel the goat
representing Azazel or the goat that
points to the
Lord the man that was to lead the goat
out into the desert he was not a priest
there's no record he was just as a fit
man but I need you to note this it says
in Leviticus 16:26 and he that let go
the goat for the scapegoat shall wash
his clothes and bathe his flesh in water
and afterward comes why is he filthy if
all he did was lead the scapegoat out
into the
Wilderness there's no sacrifice there's
no blood all he does is he takes the
goat by Accord walks him out into the
Wilderness and comes back he's got to
wash his clothes wash his
flesh why
I tell you what here's what the Bible
says when the unclean spirit is gone out
of a man he walketh through Dry places
that word is translated as desert
y'all a
Wilderness seeking rest and findeth none
then he sayith I will return unto my
house from whence I came out and when he
cometh he finds it empty that is clean
swept and garnished I need y'all to
understand that the sanctuary was a
miniature model of how God expects to
get sin out of his people and the one
thing beloved that will happen is God
will ultimately remove that evil spirit
from his people from his house that evil
spirit will go into the Wilderness to be
banished Forever at a certain
time and this is what so many people do
not understand the Bible says that he
will go into a land that is not
inhabited so let's break this down and
then we're done what is this land that
is not inhabited
where no one
is in Jeremiah 6:8 the Bible says be
thou instructed Jerusalem let my lest my
soul depart from thee lest I make thee
desolate a land not inhabited so I need
y'all to understand that the term
desolate also equates with a land not
inhabited when the goat is sent out into
a land not inhabited it's saying the
goat is sent out into a desolate place
doesn't sound like Jesus's Destiny to
me thus say the Lord curse be the man
that trusteth in man and maketh flesh's
arm and whose heart departeth from the
Lord who are those that are sent out
those whose hearts are departed from the
Lord for he shall be like the heath in
the desert in the desert and shall not
see when good comes but he shall inhabit
the parched places in the wilderness
and an assault
land and not inhabited I need y'all to
understand this beloved that when the
Bible speaks about a place not inhabited
it is speaking about a desolate place
that is for the
Wicked This is why the Bible says in
Revelation 20 ver1 and I'll just do the
rest of this without any more verses I'm
done you're going to get the rest of my
verses in Revelation 20 Beloved the
Bible talks about this Angel descending
from heaven and laying hands on Satan
and sending him into a place called The
Abyss but if you go over to Jeremiah CH
4 verse 23 you will see that that Abyss
is the is described as an earth that is
desolate like a
Wilderness and Satan beloved that Azazel
that goat that is against the Lord will
be sent into the Wilderness of this
Earth which will be desolate for a
thousand years and there beloved he will
Bear all the punishment of everything
he's ever done in this world to cause
destruction and sin and death and now
and now for my closing argument see I am
done I gotta close with this y'all
because this is good
news come come y'all got to see these
verses and one story one story and then
we're done y'all will know this story
y'all will know this story Josh chapter
7 let let let me set it up come back
come back children of Israel are
supposed to go out and fight AI they go
out to fight Ai and they get beat up
they get beat badly Joshua is like what
happened because we just won the Battle
of Jericho how did we lose this and then
God says Something's Happened in the
camp and I need you to find it out I
need you to go do what I'm going to tell
you to do so notice what the Bible says
in the morning therefore shall you shall
you shall be brought according to your
tribes
and it shall be that the tribe which the
lord taketh now let me pause here and
just show you what that word taketh
means it means to catch in a
trap or a pit generally to capture or
occupy also to choose by lot to choose
by lot I need y'all to understand this
here what's about to happen is a casting
of
lots why because they're trying to find
out who is the cause of their loss to AI
so the Bible says it shall let's go back
let's go back uh um whoever shall the
Lord shall take that is casting lots
shall come according to the families
thereof and the family which the Lord
shall take shall come by household and
the household which the Lord shall take
shall come Man by man and it shall be
that he that is taken with the accursed
thing shall be burnt with fire he and
all that he has because he has
transgressed the Covenant of the Lord
and because he has wrought Folly in
Israel so Joshua rose up early in the
morning and brought Israel by their
tribes and the tribe of Judah was taken
and he brought the family of Judah and
he took the family of the Zar heits and
he brought the family of the Zar heits
Man by man and zabdi was taken and he
brought the household of Man by man and
aen the son of Cari the son of zabdi the
son of Zarah the tribe of Judah was
taken and Joshua said unto Aken my son
give I pray thee glory to the Lord God
of Israel and make confession unto him
tell me now now what thou Hast done hide
it not from me and y'all get the story
right the story is aen took a Babylonia
garment and hid it among his stuff and
so they go to ain's tent and they they
see the stuff there and they take
everyone that was part of ain's
lot and they brought him out into a
valley do y'all understand this this was
judgment taking place and the people of
God could not Advance while the evil was
among them and so what
happened
Lots I need y'all to understand beloved
that ultimately Satan
it the lot is going to fall on Satan and
listen to me all that he has all that
pertaineth to him all who belong all who
are part of his family
all who chose Babylon over Jerusalem all
who chose the wine of Babylon the
teachings of Babylon the stuff of
Babylon all who chose
this and beloved here's the sad
thing some people are so
bent on what they know not
that they will hear all this and still
be like yep
nope because Ellen White
said yeah no because I heard you guys
are a
cult I need to see in the
chat so please tell me
which goat do you
choose do you choose the Lord's goat or
do you choose as a
zel you put a one in the chat for me for
the Lord's goat I'm not even going to
give you the option I mean you put two
if you want to don't put it in the chat
please if you choose the Lord's goat
over Azazel you go ahead and put that
one in the
chat you go ahead and put that one in
the chat I do not want to be a part of
Akin Akin's
family Akin's crew the fire is prepared
for the devil and his angels God didn't
prepare for human beings but human
beings are nosy and they like what
Satan's doing they're like man what you
doing Satan and they fall for what
Satan's doing and let me tell you
beloved again let me say it again if
anyone tells
you that you should be worshiping as AEL
do me a favor just go to Google just go
to Google go whatever AI chat you CH
just go to Google and show them Azel
type it in the chat and tell me what you
see and then let them explain to you why
no no no it's okay you know that was a
different Azazel but this Azazel is the
good
Azazel because there is a good Azazel
and a bad
Azel
yeah Heavenly Father
Lord please open the eyes of your people
you have sincere people Lord in every
church people that may be misguided but
they're sincere people that are zealous
like like Saul before he became Paul
they're
sincere please Lord Open the Eyes of
your people that they may see just how
diabolical Azazel
is just how diabolic IAL as AEL is he
doesn't want them to understand the
identity of you know of of himself in
the day of atonement because if they
understand that then that's going to
lead to a correct understanding of what
the day of atonement is about what the
judgment is about which is going to lead
to a correct understanding of that 2300
day prophecy which is going to lead to a
correct understanding of why the law of
God is so important because there is a
judgment a correct understanding of how
law and Grace go hand in hand not one
canceling the other and and the doesn't
want all this so he
just he finds the most convenient
ways to lull people into sleep
mode like the video said in the
beginning I'm going to put this on sleep
mode Lord help us never to be on sleep
mode because it is while men slept that
the enemy came in and sow tears among
the wheat
please Lord open our eyes teach us how
to study in depth the word of God so
that we don't take any man's word for it
that man's word may be truth and it may
be error but let us prove it for
ourselves thank you Lord for hearing and
answering this prayer because we ask it
in the precious and holy name of Jesus
Amen and amen I want to thank you all um
I want to thank you all for uh
uh having the patience of the Saints
having the patience of the Saints may
God bless you I think we're going to put
the uh the the uh QR code there it is at
the bottom of the screen so if you're on
your phone I believe you can just press
the link if you're on your computer or
you're watching on a TV uh take a
picture scan the QR code and uh you will
get access to these slides may God bless
you as you continue to study for those
of you who are visi visiting with us
today um I pray that you will search us
for yourself
and uh may the Lord bless you as you as
you search for truth with a with a
humble heart and a humble
Spirit may God bless you